<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dataset>
  <sequence>
    <author>Mr. Robert D. Bauman, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North ·carolina 27711. Mr. Michael A. Berry, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr. Ronald L. Bradow, Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Ms. F. Vandiver P. Bradow,</author>
    <title>Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agepcy, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</title>
    <author>Dr. Robert M. Bruce,</author>
    <title>Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office,-Office of Research and Development, U.S.</title>
    <journal>Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina</journal>
    <volume>27711.</volume>
    <author>Dr. J. Michael Davis, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr. Kenneth L. Demerjian,</author>
    <title>Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S.</title>
    <container-title>Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</container-title>
    <editor>Dr. Jack L. Durham,</editor>
    <container-title>Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Mr. ThomasG. Ellestad, Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</container-title>
    <note>Dr. J. H. B. Garner, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr. Judith A. Graham, Health Effects Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr. Lester D. Grant, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr. Steven M.</author>
    <title>Horvath, lnstitute of Environmental Stress, University of California, Santa Barbara, California 93106. Mr. James Kawecki, Center for Health and Environmental Studies, Biospherics Incorporated, Rockville, Maryland 20852. Dr. Si Duk Lee, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S.</title>
    <journal>Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina</journal>
    <volume>27711.</volume>
    <author>Dr. Daniel B. Menzel, Department of Pharmacology and Medicine, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina 27710. Dr. Frederick J. Miller, Health Effects Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park,</author>
    <title>North Carolina 27711.</title>
    <container-title>Mr. ThomasB. McMullen, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North. Carolina 27711. Mr. Charles E. Rodes, Environmental Monitoring Systems Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</container-title>
    <note>Dr. David E. Weil, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr. Jack L. Durham,</author>
    <title>Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory; Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</title>
    <author>Contributors Dr. Kenneth L. Demerjian,</author>
    <title>Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research.and Development, U.S.</title>
    <journal>Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park,</journal>
    <note>North Carolina 27711.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr. Harold M. Barnes, Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr. William E. Wilson, Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Reviewers Dr. A. Paul Altshuller,</author>
    <title>Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr. Bruce Appel, Air and Industrial Hygiene Labs, California Department of Health Services,</title>
    <location>Berkeley, California .94704.</location>
    <publisher>Dr. James Brock, University of Texas,</publisher>
    <location>Austin, Texas</location>
    <citation-number>78712.</citation-number>
    <author>Dr.</author>
    <title>Warren Galke, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S..</title>
    <container-title>Environmental Protection Agency, Research .Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr. Walter John, Air and Industrial Hygiene Labs, California Department of Health Services,</container-title>
    <location>San Francisco, California.</location>
    <publisher>Dr. Dale Lungren, University of Florida,</publisher>
    <location>Gainesville, Florida 32611.</location>
    <publisher>Dr. Robin Martin, Aerospace Corporation,</publisher>
    <location>Los Angeles, California.</location>
    <note>' ' Mr. ThomasB. McMullen,</note>
    <journal>Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office,. Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triang'le Park,</journal>
    <note>North Carolina 27711. ,J :,, ' Dr. David Natusch, Department of Chemistry, Colorado State Univ~rsity, Fort. Collins, Colorado 80523. • Dr. Leonard Newman,Brookhaven National Labs, Upton, NewYork 11973.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr. David Pui,</author>
    <title>Mechanical Engineering Department,</title>
    <publisher>University of Minnesota,</publisher>
    <location>Minneapolis, Minnesota</location>
    <citation-number>55455.</citation-number>
    <author>Mr. Robert Shaw,</author>
    <title>Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Res.earcti and Oevel opment, U.S.</title>
    <author>Environmenta1 .</author>
    <title>Protect ion Agency,</title>
    <journal>Research Triangl,e Park, North Carolina</journal>
    <volume>27711..</volume>
    <author>Dr. Roger Tanner, Brookhaven National Labs, Upton,</author>
    <title>NewYork 11973.</title>
    <publisher>Dr. James Wedding, Colorado State University, Fort Collins,</publisher>
    <location>Colorado 80523.</location>
    <note>Dr. Kenneth Whitby, Mechanical Engineering Department,</note>
    <publisher>University of Minnesota,</publisher>
    <location>Minneapolis, Minnesota 55455.</location>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Mr. Larry J. Purdue, Environmental Monitoring Systems Laborator.y, Office of Research and Deve1opment, U.S. E.nvironmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina.</author>
    <pages>27711.</pages>
    <author>Mr. Kenneth A. Rehme, Environmental Monitoring Systems Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Mr. Charles E. Rodes, Environmental Monitoring Systems Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. V. Ross Highsmith,</author>
    <title>Environmental Monitoring Systems Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. • Contributors Mr. ThomasHartlage, Environmental Monitoring Systems Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Mr. James Kawecki, Center for Health and Environmental Studies, Biospherics Incorporated,</title>
    <location>Rockville, Maryland</location>
    <container-title>20852. Dr. William McClenny, Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Reviewers Dr. Bruce Appel, Air and Industrial Hygiene Labs, California Department of Health Services,</container-title>
    <location>Berkeley, California 94704.</location>
    <publisher>Dr. James Brock, University of Texas,</publisher>
    <location>Austin, Texas 78712.</location>
    <note>Dr. Robert J. Charlson, Department of Atmospheric Chemistry,</note>
    <publisher>University of Washington,</publisher>
    <location>Seattle, Washington 98195.</location>
    <publisher>Dr. Douglas Dockery, Harvard School of Public Health,</publisher>
    <location>Boston, Massachusetts 02115.</location>
    <note>Dr. Warren A. Galke, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr. ThomasR. Hauser, Environmental Monitoring Systems Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research • Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr.</author>
    <title>John Holmes, California Air Resources Board,</title>
    <location>Sacramento, California</location>
    <citation-number>95819~</citation-number>
    <author>Dr. Walter John, Air and Industrial Hygiene Labs, California Department of Health Services, San Francisco, California. Dr. Daris Levaggi, Bay Area Air Quality ManagementDistrict, San Francisco, California. Dr.</author>
    <title>Dale Lungren, Environmental Engineering Department,</title>
    <publisher>University of Florida,</publisher>
    <location>Gainesville, Florida</location>
    <citation-number>32611.</citation-number>
    <author>Mr. ThomasB. McMullen,</author>
    <title>Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</title>
    <publisher>Dr. David Natusch, Department of Chemistry, Colorado State University, Fort Collins,</publisher>
    <genre>Colorado 80523.</genre>
    <author>Dr. Leonard Newman,Brookhaven National Labs, Upton,</author>
    <title>NewYork 11973.</title>
    <publisher>Dr. David Pui, Mechanical Engineering Department, University of Minnesota,</publisher>
    <location>Minneapolis, Minnesota</location>
    <container-title>55455. Ms. Laura.Scoville, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Mr. Robert Shaw, Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Mr. Robert Stevens, Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</container-title>
    <note>Dr. Roger Tanner, Brookhaven National Labs, Upton, NewYork 11973. Dr. James Wedding, Engineering Research Center, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, Colorado 80523.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr. James N. Braddock,</author>
    <title>Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S.</title>
    <genre>Environmental Protection Agency,</genre>
    <publisher>Research Triangle Park,</publisher>
    <location>North Carolina 27711.</location>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Mr.</author>
    <title>Jeff Meling,</title>
    <publisher>Radian Corporation,</publisher>
    <location>Austin, Texas.</location>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr. John W. Winchester, Department of Oceanography, Florida State University, Tallahassee, Florida .32306. Cootributors Dr. Lester D. Grant,</author>
    <title>Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S.</title>
    <container-title>Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. • Mr. Thomas8. McMullen, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 277.11.</container-title>
    <publisher>Mr. Elmer Robinson, Chemical Engineering Department, Washington State University,</publisher>
    <location>Pullman, Washington 99164.</location>
    <note>Reviewers Or. August T. Rossano, Civil Engineering Department,</note>
    <publisher>University of Washington,</publisher>
    <location>Seattle, Washington 98195.</location>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Or. Ronald L Bradow, Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Ag~ncy, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr.</author>
    <title>John 0. Spengler, Environmental Health, Harvard School of Public Health,</title>
    <location>Boston, Massachusetts</location>
    <citation-number>02115.</citation-number>
    <author>Contributor Or. John S. Evans, Environmental Health, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston,</author>
    <title>Massachusetts 02115.</title>
    <journal>Mr. Douglas</journal>
    <volume>8.</volume>
    <author>Fennell, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park,</author>
    <title>North Carolina 27711. Reviewers Dr.</title>
    <publisher>Robert Br.aman,Department of Chemistry, University of South Florida,</publisher>
    <location>Tampa, Florida</location>
    <citation-number>33620.</citation-number>
    <author>Dr. Cliff I. Davidson,</author>
    <title>Department of Civil Engineering,</title>
    <publisher>Carnegie-Me11on University,</publisher>
    <location>Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</location>
    <edition>15213. Dr.</edition>
    <publisher>Douglas Dockery, Harvard School of Public Health,</publisher>
    <location>Boston, Massachusetts</location>
    <citation-number>02115.</citation-number>
    <author>Dr.</author>
    <title>John Holmes, Research Division, ·california Air Resources Board, Sacramento, California 95812.</title>
    <publisher>Dr. Paul Lioy, Institute of Environmental Medicine, NewYork University Medical Center,</publisher>
    <location>NewYork,</location>
    <volume>NewYork 10016.</volume>
    <author>Dr. James P. Lodge, Boulder, Colorado 80303. Mr. Thomas B. McMullen,· Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency,</author>
    <title>Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</title>
    <publisher>Dr. Kenneth E. Noll, Department of Environmental Engineering, Illinois Institute of Technology,</publisher>
    <location>Chicago, Illinois</location>
    <editor>60616. Dr. August T. Rossano,</editor>
    <genre>Civil Engineering Department,</genre>
    <publisher>University of Washington,</publisher>
    <location>Seattle, Washington 98195.</location>
    <note>Chapter 6. Atmospheric Transport, Transformation and Deposition Principal Author Dr. Kenneth L. Demerjian, Environme~tal Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Reviewers Dr. "A. Paul Altshuller, Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, . Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr. Frank Binkowski, Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park,</author>
    <title>North Carolina 27711. Dr. Jeremy Hale, Battelle Pacific Northwest Research Laboratory, -Richland, Washington 99352.</title>
    <publisher>Dr. Rudolf Husar, Department of Mechanical Engineering, Washington University, St. Louis,</publisher>
    <location>Missouri</location>
    <container-title>63130. Dr·. Paul Lioy, Institute of Environmental Medicine, NewYork University Medical Center, NewYork, NewYork 10016. Mr. Thomas B. McMullen, Environmental Criteria and Asse~sment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</container-title>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr, Jarvis L. Moyers,</author>
    <title>Department of Chemistry,</title>
    <publisher>University of Arizona,</publisher>
    <location>Tucson, Arizona 85721.</location>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr. Kenneth E. Noll,</author>
    <title>Department of Environmental Engineering, Illinois Institute of Technology,</title>
    <location>Chicago, Illinois</location>
    <citation-number>60616.</citation-number>
    <author>Dr. August T. Rossano,</author>
    <title>Civil Engineering Department,</title>
    <publisher>University of Washington,</publisher>
    <location>Seattle, Washington</location>
    <citation-number>98195.</citation-number>
    <author>Dr. Jack Shreffler,</author>
    <title>Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S.</title>
    <journal>Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park,</journal>
    <note>North Carolina 27711. Dr. Warren H. White, CAPITA,St. Louis, Missouri 63130. Chapter 7. Acidic Deposition</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr. Joan Baker, School of Forestry and Environmental Studies, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina 27706. Dr. J .. H. B. Garner,</author>
    <title>Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</title>
    <author>Contributors Mr. Angelo P. Capparella, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park,</author>
    <title>North Carolina 27711.</title>
    <journal>Dr. J. Michael Davis, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park,</journal>
    <note>North Carolina 27711. Reviewers Dr. Martin Alexander, Department of Agronomy,Cornell University, Ithaca, NewYork 14853.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Or. David S. Anthony, Department of Botany, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida 32611. Dr. Carl W. Chen, Tetratech, Inc.,</author>
    <title>Lafayette, California 94549.</title>
    <note>Dr. Charles Cogbill, Private Consultant, Denver, Colorado 80220.</note>
    <author>Or. Ellis B. Cowling, School of Forest Resources,</author>
    <publisher>North Carolina State University,</publisher>
    <location>Raleigh, North Carolina</location>
    <date>27650.</date>
    <note>Dr. Lance S. Evans, Department of Biology, Manhattan College, Bronx, New York 10471.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Mr. Patrick J. Festa, Bureau of Fisheries, NewYork State Department of Environmental Conservation, Albany, NewYork 12233. Dr. Robert A. Goldstein,</author>
    <title>Environmental Assessment Department, Electric Power Research Institute, Palo Alto, California 94303.</title>
    <author>Dr. Bertil Hagerhall, Ministry of Agriculture, Stockholm, Sweden. Dr. George R. Hendrey,</author>
    <title>Department of Energy and Environment, Brookhaven National Laboratory, Upton, NewYork 11973.</title>
    <author>Dr. Patricia M. Irving,</author>
    <title>Argonne National Laboratories, Argonne, Illinois 60439.</title>
    <author>Dr. Jay S. Jacobson,</author>
    <title>Boyce ThompsonInstitute at Cornell University, Ithaca, NewYork 14853. Dr. Rick Linthurst, Botany Department,</title>
    <publisher>North Carolina State University,</publisher>
    <location>Raleigh, North Carolina</location>
    <pages>27650.</pages>
    <author>Dr. Samuel N. Linzon, Air Resources Branch, Ontario Ministry of the Environment, Toronto, Canada. Dr. William W. McFee, Natural Resources and Environmental Sciences, Purdue University, West Lafayette,</author>
    <title>Indiana 47907.</title>
    <container-title>Dr. Charles Powers, Environmental Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency,</container-title>
    <location>Corvallis, Oregon 97330.</location>
    <note>Dr. Carl L. Schofield, Department of Natural Resources,•Cornell University, Ithaca, NewYork 14853.</note>
    <publisher>Dr. David Shriner, Oak Ridge National Laboratory,</publisher>
    <location>Oak Ridge, Tennessee 37830.</location>
    <publisher>Dr. David Weber, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency,</publisher>
    <location>Washington, D.C.</location>
    <note>20460. Chapter 8. Effects on Vegetation</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Mr. Michael A. Berry, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Mr. Angelo P. Capparella, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr. J. H. B. Garner, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr. Lester D. Grant, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr. Sagar V. Krupa,</author>
    <title>Department of Plant Pathology, University of Minnesota, St.</title>
    <journal>Paul, Minnesota</journal>
    <volume>55108.</volume>
    <author>• Dr. George E. Taylor, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Oak Ridge,</author>
    <genre>Tennessee 37830.</genre>
    <publisher>Reviewers Dr. Donald Davis, Pennsylvania State University, State College,</publisher>
    <location>Pennsylvania</location>
    <author>168Ql.· Dr. Lance S. Evans, Department of Biology, Manhattan College, NewYork,</author>
    <journal>NewYork</journal>
    <volume>10471.</volume>
    <author>Dr. Walter Heck, Science and Education Administration, U.S. Department of Agriculture,</author>
    <title>Botany Department,</title>
    <publisher>North Carolina State University,</publisher>
    <location>Raleigh, North Carolina</location>
    <pages>27650.</pages>
    <author>Dr. Allen Heagle,</author>
    <title>Science and Education Administration, U.S.</title>
    <publisher>Department of Agriculture, Department of Plant Pathology, North Carolina State University,</publisher>
    <location>Raleigh, North Carolina·</location>
    <pages>27650.</pages>
    <publisher>Dr. HowardE. Heggestad, Science and Education Administration, U.S. Department of Agriculture,</publisher>
    <location>Beltsville, Maryland 20705.</location>
    <note>Dr. Herbert C. Jones, Air Resources Program, Tennessee Valley Authority, Muscle Shoals, Alabama 35660. Dr. Allan 1:1.Legge,</note>
    <publisher>Environmental Science Center, University of .Calgary,</publisher>
    <location>Alberta, Canada.</location>
    <note>Dr. Samuel N. Linzon, Air Resources Branch, Ontario Ministry of the Environment, Toronto, Canada. Dr. Delbert C. McCune,Boyce ThompsonInstitute at Cornell University, Ithaca, NewYork 14853. liv Dr. David Shriner, Oak Ridge National· Laboratory, Oak Ridge, Tennessee 37830.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr. RaymondWilhour, Environmental Research Laboratory, Office of.Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Corvallis,</author>
    <title>Oregon 97330. Chapter 9.</title>
    <container-title>Effects ·on Visibility and Climate Principal Authors Mr. ThomasG. Ellestad, Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</container-title>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Mr. James Kawecki,</author>
    <title>Center for Health and Environmental Studies,</title>
    <location>Biospherics, Incorporated, Rockville, Maryland</location>
    <citation-number>20852.</citation-number>
    <author>Contributors Ms. F. Vandiver P. Bradow,</author>
    <title>Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</title>
    <publisher>Dr. Rudolf Husar, Department of Mechanical Engineering, Washington University, St. Louis,</publisher>
    <location>Missouri</location>
    <container-title>63130. • Dr.</container-title>
    <location>David Patterson, CAPITA,</location>
    <publisher>Washington University, St. Louis,</publisher>
    <location>Missouri 63130.</location>
    <publisher>Dr. Charles Sternheim, University of Maryland,</publisher>
    <location>College Park, Maryland 20742.</location>
    <note>Dr. Warren H. White, CAPITA,Washington University, St. Louis, Missouri 63130.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Ms.-F. Vandiver P. Bradow, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle ·Park, North Carolina 27711. Contributors Mr. Michael A. Berry, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. lv Dr. John A. Jaksch, Rogers, Golden &amp; Halpern, Reston, Virginia 22091. Mr. James Kawecki,</author>
    <title>Center for Health and Environmental Studies, Biospherics, Incorporated, Rockville,.</title>
    <journal>Mary.land</journal>
    <volume>20852.</volume>
    <author>Dr.</author>
    <title>David Maase, Center for Health and Environmental Studies, Biospherics, Incorporated, Rockville, Maryland 20852.</title>
    <author>Dr. Victor S. Salvin, University of North Carolina, Greensboro,</author>
    <title>North Carolina 27408.</title>
    <author>Reviewers Dr. Ronald L. Bradow,</author>
    <title>Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S.</title>
    <journal>Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina</journal>
    <volume>27711.</volume>
    <author>Dr. Donald J. Gillette,</author>
    <title>Health Effects Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development,</title>
    <author>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Mr.. Fred Haynie, Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park,</author>
    <title>North Carolina 27711.</title>
    <publisher>Dr. James P. Lodge,</publisher>
    <location>Boulder, Colorado</location>
    <container-title>80303. Mr. ThomasB. McMullen, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection.Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Mr. John W. Spence, Regional Support Services, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</container-title>
    <note>Mr. James B. Upham,Environmental Sciences Research Laboratory, Office of R·esearch and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr. Phillippus Willems, Biospherics, Incorporated, Rockville, Maryland 20852. Mr. John Yocom,TRCEnvironmental Consultants, Wethersfield, Connecticut 06109.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <title>Biological Fate of Inhaled Aerosols and so2 Principal Authors Mr.</title>
    <author>Fred~rick J. Miller,</author>
    <title>Health Effects Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S.</title>
    <publisher>Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park,</publisher>
    <location>North Carolina 27711.</location>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr. Otto G. Raabe,</author>
    <title>Department of Civil Engineering,</title>
    <publisher>University of California,</publisher>
    <location>Davis, California 95616:</location>
    <publisher>Contributors Ms. Margaret Grady, Northrop Services, Inc., Research Triangle Park~ North Carolina</publisher>
    <pages>27709.</pages>
    <author>Pr. Amit Patra, Northrop Services, Inc., Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27709. Or. David E. Weil, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Reviewers Dr. Douglas Craig, Toxicology Division, Litton Bionetics, Rockville,</author>
    <title>Maryland 20850. Dr. Richard Cuddihy, Lovelace Biomedical and Environmental Research Institute, Albuquerque, NewMexico 87115. Dr. Warren Johnson, SRI International, Menlo Park, California 94025. Dr. George Kanapilly, Lovelace Biomedical and Environmental Research Institute, Albuquerque, NewMexico 87115. Dr. MyronMehlman,Toxicology Division, Mobil Oil Corporation, Princeton, New•Jersey 08540.</title>
    <publisher>Dr. Paul Morrow, University of Rochester Medical Center,</publisher>
    <location>Rochester, NewYork</location>
    <citation-number>14642.</citation-number>
    <author>Dr. Mohammad Mustafa, School of Public Health, University of California, Los Angeles,</author>
    <title>California 90024.</title>
    <publisher>Dr. Robert Phalen, Department of Communityand Environmental Medicine, University of California,</publisher>
    <location>Irvine, California</location>
    <edition>92717. Dr.</edition>
    <location>David L.</location>
    <publisher>Swift, School of Hygiene.and Public Health, The Johns Hopkins University,</publisher>
    <location>Baltimore, Maryland 21205.</location>
    <publisher>Dr. Walter Tyler, Department of Anatomy, California Primate Research Center, University of California,</publisher>
    <location>Davis, California 95616.</location>
    <note>Dr. Ron Wolff, Lovelace Biomedical and Environmental Research Institute, Albuquerque, NewMexico 87115. Dr. C. P. Yu, Department of Engineering Science, State University of NewYork at Buffalo, Buffalo, NewYork 14214.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>.Principal Authors Dr. Judith A. Graham, Health Effects Research Laboratory, Office of·Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr. Daniel B. Menzel, Department of Pharmacology and Medicine, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina 27710. Ms. Elaine Smolko, Department of Pharmacology and Medicine, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina 27710. Contributors Mr. Steven Silbaugh, Duke University, Durham,</author>
    <title>North Carolina 27710. Dr. Vic Hasselblad, Health Effects Research Laboratory, Qffi.ce of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr. AndrewStead, Health Effects Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</title>
    <author>Dr. David E. Weil,</author>
    <title>Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, u.s~Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park,.North Carolina 27711.</title>
    <author>Dr. M. Jean Wiester,</author>
    <title>Health Effects Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development,</title>
    <author>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Reviewers Dr. Douglas K. Craig, Toxicology Division, Litton Bionetics, Rockville, Maryland 20850. • Dr.</author>
    <title>T.</title>
    <publisher>Timothy Crocker, College of Medicine, University of California,</publisher>
    <location>Irvine, California</location>
    <edition>92717. Dr.</edition>
    <location>Richard Ehrlich,</location>
    <publisher>IIT Research Institute,</publisher>
    <location>Chicago, Illinois</location>
    <container-title>60616. Dr. Jack HacKney,Rancho Los AmigosHospital, Downey,California 90242. Dr. F. Gordpn Hueter, Health Effects Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr. MyronMehlman,Toxicology Division, Mobil Oil Corporation, Princeton, NewJersey· 08540. lviii Dr.</container-title>
    <publisher>Paul Morrow, University of Rochester Medical Center,</publisher>
    <location>Rochester, New York 14642.</location>
    <note>• Dr. Mohammed Mustafa, School of Public Health, University of Cali.fornia, Los Angeles, California 90024.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr. Joseph Santodonato, Li.fe and Material Science Division, Syracuse Research Corporation, Syracuse,</author>
    <title>NewYork 13210. Dr. Robert Shapiro, Department of Chemistry, NewYork University, NewYork, NewYork 10003.</title>
    <publisher>Dr. Walter Tyler, Department of Anatomy, California Primate Research Center, University of California at Davis,</publisher>
    <location>Davis, California.</location>
    <note>95616. Dr. Ron Wolff, Lovelace Biomedical and Environmental Research Institute, Albuquerque, NewYork 87115.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr. Steven M. ·Horvath,</author>
    <title>Insti.tute of Environmental Stress,</title>
    <publisher>University of California,</publisher>
    <location>Santa Barbara, California</location>
    <citation-number>93106.</citation-number>
    <author>Contributors Dr. Robert M. Bruce, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr. J. Michael Davis,</author>
    <title>Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</title>
    <author>Dr. Lester D. Grant, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr. David J. McKee, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office;</author>
    <title>Office of Research and Development, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</title>
    <publisher>Reviewers Gr. HomerBoushey, Cardiovascular Res~arch Institute, University of .</publisher>
    <location>California, San Francisco, California 94143.</location>
    <note>Dr. Phillip Bromberg,·Department of Medicine, University of North Carolina, Chap_elHill, North Carolina 27514. Dr. Anthony Colucci, Colucci and Associates, Morgan Hill, California 95037. l ix Dr. Douglas K. Craig, Toxicology Division, Litton Bionetics, Rockville, Maryland 20850.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr. Richard Cuddihy, Lovelace Biomedical and Environmental Research Institute, Albuquerque,</author>
    <title>NewMexico 87115. Dr. Richard Ehrlich, IIT Research institute, Chicago, Illinois 60616.</title>
    <publisher>Dr. Robert Frank, Environmental Health, University of Washington,</publisher>
    <location>Seattle, Washington</location>
    <citation-number>98195.</citation-number>
    <author>Dr. Jack Hackney,</author>
    <title>Rancho Los Amigos Hospital, Downey,California 90242.</title>
    <note>Dr. Milan Hazucha, Center for Environmental Health, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, North Carolina 27$14. Dr. ThomasJ. Kulle, School of Medicine,</note>
    <publisher>University of Maryland,</publisher>
    <location>Baltimore, Maryland</location>
    <container-title>21201. Dr. MyronMehlman,Toxicology Division, Mobil Oil Corporation, Princeton,, NewJersey 08540. Dr. Donald Proctor, The Johns Hopkins School of Hygiene,</container-title>
    <location>Baltimore, Maryland •</location>
    <edition>21205. Dr.</edition>
    <location>David L.</location>
    <publisher>Swift, The Johns ~opkins University,</publisher>
    <location>Baltimore, Maryland 21205.</location>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr. Lester D. Grant, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of, Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Rese~rch Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Contributors Dr. Benjamin G. Ferris,</author>
    <title>Harvard School of Public Health,</title>
    <location>Boston, Massachusetts</location>
    <citation-number>02115.</citation-number>
    <author>Dr. Warren A. Galke,</author>
    <title>Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S.</title>
    <container-title>Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711.</container-title>
    <publisher>Dr. Victor Hasselblad, Health Effects Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina</publisher>
    <pages>27711.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr. Dennis J. Kotchmar, Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. Dr. Michael D. Lebowitz,</author>
    <title>Arizona Health Sciences Center, Tucson, Arizona 85724.</title>
    <publisher>Dr. Frank Speizer, Harvard School of Public Health,</publisher>
    <location>Boston, Massachusetts</location>
    <citation-number>02115.</citation-number>
    <author>Or. James H. Ware, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston,</author>
    <title>Massachusetts 02115. Reviewers Dr~ Karim Ahmed,Natural Resources Counsel, NewYork, NewYork 10017.</title>
    <author>Dr. ·Albert Bennett, St. Georges Hospital, London, England. Dr. Steven D. Colome,</author>
    <title>Harvard School of Public Health,</title>
    <location>Boston, Massachusetts</location>
    <citation-number>02115.</citation-number>
    <author>Dr.</author>
    <title>Anthony Colucci, Colucci and Associates, MorganHill, California 95037. Dr. Inga Goldstein, Division of Epidemiology, Columbia University, NewYork, NewYork 10032.</title>
    <note>Dr. Douglas I. Hammer,Private Consultant, Raleigh, North CaroJina 27607. Dr. Ian T. Higgins, School of Public Health, University of Micpigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109. Dr. LawrenceHinkle, Cornell University Medical School, NewYork, NewYork 10021. Dr. EmanuelLandau, Environmental Health Hazards Project, Chevy Chase, Maryland 20015. Dr. Gory J. Love, Institute for Environmental Studies, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, North Carolina 27514. Dr. Thaddeus J. Murawski, NewYork Department of Health, Albany, New York 12337. Dr. Herbert Schimm~l, Neurology Department, Albert Einstein Medical College, Pleasantville, NewYork 10570. Dr. Carl M. Shy, Institute far Environmental Studies, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, North Carolina 27514. Dr. Larry Thibodeau, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, Massachusetts 02115.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Or. Mary Amdur,</author>
    <title>Department of ~utrition and Food Science,</title>
    <publisher>Massachusetts Institute of Technology,</publisher>
    <location>Cambridge, Massachusetts</location>
    <citation-number>02139.</citation-number>
    <author>Dr. Judy A. Bean, College of Medicine, Department of.</author>
    <title>Preventive Medicine and Environmental Health, University of Iowa, Iowa City, Iowa 52242. Consultants Dr. EdwardCrandall, Division of Pulmonary Disease, Department of Medicine, University of California at Los Angeles,</title>
    <location>Los Angeles, California,</location>
    <date>90024.</date>
    <note>. Dr. Bernard Goldstein, Rutgers University Medical School, Department of Environmental and CommunityMedicine; Piscataway, NewJersey 08854 Dr.</note>
    <publisher>Herschel Griffin, San Diego State University, School of Public Health,</publisher>
    <location>San Diego, California 92192.</location>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dr, Timothy Larson, Department of Civil Enginee·ring, Mail Stop FC-05,</author>
    <publisher>University of Washington,</publisher>
    <location>Seattle, Washington</location>
    <citation-number>98195.</citation-number>
    <author>Or.</author>
    <title>Morton Lippmann, Institute of Environmental Medicine, New York University, NewYork, NewYork 10016.</title>
    <note>Or. Roger 0. McClellan, Director of Inhalation Toxicology Research Institute, ~ovelace Foundation, P.O. Box 5890, Albuquerque, NewMexico 87115 lxiii.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Abe, M.</author>
    <title>Effects of mixed nitrogen dioxide-sulfur dioxide on humanpulmonary functions.</title>
    <journal>Bull. Tokyo Med. Dent. Univ.</journal>
    <volume>14:415-433,</volume>
    <date>1967.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Adkins, B., Jr., G. H. Luginbuhl, F. J. Miller, and D. E. Gardner.</author>
    <title>Increased pulmonary susceptibility to streptococcal infection following inhalation of manganeseoxide.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Res.</journal>
    <volume>23:110-120,</volume>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Adkins, B., Jr., J. H. Richards, and D. E. Gardner.</author>
    <title>Enhancementof experimental respiratory infection following nickel inhalation.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Res.</journal>
    <volume>20:</volume>
    <pages>33-42,</pages>
    <date>1979.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Alarie, Y. C., A. A. Krumm,W. M. Busey, C. E. Ulrich, and R. J. Kantz.</author>
    <title>Long-term exposure to sulfur dioxide, sulfuric acid mist, fly ash, and their mixtures. Results of studies in monkeysand guinea pigs.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>30:254-262,</volume>
    <date>1975.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Alarie, Y., C. E. Ulrich, W. M. Busey, A. A. Krumm,and H. N. Macfarland.</author>
    <title>Long-term continuous exposure to sulfur dioxide in cynomolgusmonkeys.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>24:115-128,</volume>
    <date>1972.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Alarie, Y., C. E. Ulrich, W. M. Busey, A. A. Krumm,and H. N. Macfarland.</author>
    <title>Long-term continuous exposure to sulfur dioxide in cynomolgusmonkeys.</title>
    <container-title>In: Air Pollution and the Po1itics of Control. MSSInformation Corpor.ation,</container-title>
    <location>NewYork,</location>
    <date>1973c,</date>
    <pages>pp. 47-60.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Alarie, Y., I. Wakisaka, and S. Oka.</author>
    <title>Sensory irritation by sulfur dioxide and chlorobenzilidene malononitrile.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Physiol. Biochem.</journal>
    <volume>1:53-64,</volume>
    <pages>1973d.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Alarie, Y., R. J. Kantz II, C. E. l)lrich, A. A. Krumm,and W. M. Busey.</author>
    <title>Long-term continuous exposure to sulfur dioxide and fly ash mixtures in cynomolgusmonkeysand guinea pigs.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>27:251-253,</volume>
    <pages>1973b.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Alarie, Y., W. M., Busey, A. A. Krumm,and C. E. Ulrich.</author>
    <title>Long-term continuous exposure to sulfuric acid mist in cynomolgus monkeys and guinea pigs.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>27:16-24,</volume>
    <pages>1973a.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Amdur, M.</author>
    <title>0. The effect of aerosols on the response to irritant gases.</title>
    <editor>In: Inhaled Particles and Vapors. C. N. Davies, ed.,</editor>
    <location>PergamonPress, Oxford,</location>
    <date>1961,</date>
    <pages>pp.~81-294.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Amdur, M.</author>
    <title>0. Toxicological guidelines for research on sulfur oxides and particulates.</title>
    <container-title>In: Proceedings of the 4th Symposiumon Statistics and the Environment,</container-title>
    <location>Washington, DC,</location>
    <date>March 3-5, 1976.</date>
    <publisher>American Statistical Associatfon,</publisher>
    <location>Washington, DC,</location>
    <date>1977,</date>
    <pages>. pp.48-55.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Amdur,M. 0., and D. Underhill.</author>
    <title>The effect of ~arious aerosols on the response of guinea pigs to sulfur dioxide.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>16:460-468;</volume>
    <date>1968.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Amdur, M.</author>
    <volume>0.,</volume>
    <pages>and 0.</pages>
    <author>W. Underhill.</author>
    <title>Response of guinea pigs to a combination of sulfur dioxide and open hearth dust.</title>
    <journal>J. Air Pollut. Control Assoc.</journal>
    <volume>20:31-34,</volume>
    <date>1970.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Amdur, M. 0., J. Bayles, V. Ugro, and D. W. Underhill.</author>
    <title>Comparative irritant potency of sulfate salts.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Res.</journal>
    <volume>16:1-8,</volume>
    <pages>1978a.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Amdur, M. 0., L. Silverman, and P. Drinker.</author>
    <title>Inhalation of sulfuric acid mist by human subjects.</title>
    <journal>AMA Arch. Ind. Hyg. Occup. Med.</journal>
    <volume>&amp;:305-313,</volume>
    <date>1952.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Amdur, M. O., M.</author>
    <title>Oubriel, and 0.</title>
    <author>A. Creasia.</author>
    <title>Respiratory response of guinea pigs to low levels of sulfuric acid.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Res.</journal>
    <volume>15:418-423,</volume>
    <pages>1978b.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Amdur, M. 0., V.</author>
    <title>Ugro, and 0.</title>
    <author>W. Underhil1.</author>
    <title>Respiratory response of guinea pigs to ozone alone and with sulfur dioxide.</title>
    <journal>Am.Ind. Hyg. Assoc. J.</journal>
    <volume>39:</volume>
    <pages>958-961,</pages>
    <date>1978c.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Amdur, M. 0., W. W.. ,Melvin, Jr., and.. P. Drinker.</author>
    <title>Effects of inhalation of sulfur dioxide by man.</title>
    <journal>Lancet</journal>
    <volume>~:</volume>
    <pages>758- 759, J.953.</pages>
    <author>• Andersen, I., G. R. Lundqvist, O. F. Proctor,</author>
    <pages>and 0.</pages>
    <author>L. Swift.</author>
    <title>• Humanresponses to controlled levels of inert dust.</title>
    <journal>Am. Rev. Resp. Dis.</journal>
    <volume>119:619-627,</volume>
    <date>1979.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Andersen, I., G. R. • Lundqvist, P. L. Jensen,</author>
    <pages>and 0.</pages>
    <author>F. Proctor.</author>
    <title>·Humanresponse to controlled levels of sulfur dioxide.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>28:31-39,</volume>
    <date>1974.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Andersen, I., P. L. Jensen, S. E. Reed, J. W. Craig, O. F. Proctor, and G. K. K. Adams.</author>
    <title>Induced rhinovirus infection under controlled exposure to sulfur dioxide.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>32:120-126,</volume>
    <date>1977.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Avol, E. L., M. P. Jones, R; M. Bailey, N. M-N. Chang, M. T. Kleinman, W. S. Linn, K. A. Bell, and J. 0. Hackney.</author>
    <title>Controlled exposures of human volunteers to sulfate aerosols.</title>
    <journal>Health effects and aerosol characterization. Am. Rev. Respir. Dis.</journal>
    <volume>120:319-327,</volume>
    <date>1979.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Bailey, D. L. R., and P. Clayton.</author>
    <title>The Measurement of Suspended Particulate and Carbon Concentrations in the Atmosphere Using Standard Smoke Shade Methods.</title>
    <journal>Warren Springs Laboratory Report</journal>
    <volume>LR325(AP),</volume>
    <location>Stevenage, Hertfordshire, England,</location>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Ball, D. J. , and R. Hume.</author>
    <title>The relative importance of vehicular and domestic emissions of dark smoke in Greater London in the mid-1970 1 s;· the significance of smoke shade measurements, and an explanation of the relationship of smoke shade to gravimetric measurements of particulate.</title>
    <journal>Atmos. Environ.</journal>
    <volume>11:</volume>
    <pages>1065-1073,</pages>
    <date>1977.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Bates, D. V., and M. Hazucha.</author>
    <title>The short-term effects of ozone on the lung.</title>
    <container-title>In: Proceedings of the Conference on Health Effects of Air Pollutants, National Academy of Sciences,</container-title>
    <location>Washington; DC,</location>
    <date>October 35, 1973.</date>
    <note>Serial No. 93-15,</note>
    <publisher>U.S. Senate Committee ·on Public Works,</publisher>
    <location>Washington, DC,</location>
    <date>1973,</date>
    <pages>pp. 507-540.</pages>
    <author>' Bedi, J. F., L. J. FolinSbee, S. M. Horvath, and R. S. Ebenstein.</author>
    <title>Human exposure to sulfur dioxide and ozone: absence of a synergistic effect.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>34:233-239,</volume>
    <date>1979.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Bedi, J. F;, S. M. Horvath, and L. J. Folinsbee.</author>
    <title>Humanexposure to sulfur dioxide and ozone in a high temperature-humidity environment.</title>
    <journal>Am. Ind. Hygiene Assoc. J.,</journal>
    <date>1981</date>
    <note>(in press).</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Bell, K. A., and J. D. Hackney.</author>
    <title>Effects of sulfate aerosols upon human pulmonary function. APRAC Project CAPM-27-75. Coordinating Research Counci°'l,</title>
    <publisher>Inc.,</publisher>
    <location>New York, NY,</location>
    <date>1977.</date>
    <author>.-Bell, K. A., W. S. Linn, M. Hazucha, J. D. Hackney, and D. V. Bates.</author>
    <title>Respiratory effects of exposure to ozone p 1us sulfur dioxide in Southern Californians and Eastern Canadians.</title>
    <journal>Am. Ind. Hyg. Assoc. J.</journal>
    <volume>38:696-706,</volume>
    <date>1977.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Bradway, R. M., R. A. Record, and T. G. Pace.</author>
    <title>Application of polarizing microscopy to the • characterization of ambient suspended particulate.</title>
    <container-title>Proceedings Annual Meeting of the Federation of Analytical Chemists and Spectroscopists Society,</container-title>
    <location>Philadelphia, PA,</location>
    <date>1976.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Burton, G. G., M. Corn, J. B. L Gee, C. Vassallo, and A. P. Thomas.</author>
    <title>Response of healthy men to inhaled low concentrations of gas-aerosol mixtures.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>18:681-692,</volume>
    <date>1969.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Camp, D. C., A. L. Van Lehn, and B. W. Loo.</author>
    <title>Intercomparison of Samplers Used in the Determination of Aerosol Composition.</title>
    <container-title>EPA-600/7-78-118, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency,</container-title>
    <location>Research Triangle Park, NC,</location>
    <date>July 1978.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Cassell, E. J., D. W. Walter, J. D. Mountain, J. R. Diamond, I. M. Mountain, and J. R. Mccarroll II.</author>
    <title>Reconsiderations of mortality as as a useful index of the relationship of environmental factors to health.</title>
    <journal>Am. J. Pub. Health</journal>
    <volume>58:1653-1657,</volume>
    <date>1968.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Chan, T. L, and M. Lippmann.</author>
    <title>Experimental measurements and empirical modeling of the regional deposition of inhaled particles in humans.</title>
    <journal>Am. Ind. Hyg. Assoc. J.</journal>
    <volume>41:399-409,</volume>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Chappie, M., and L. Lave.</author>
    <title>The Health Effects of Air Pollution. A Reanalysis.</title>
    <journal>J. Urban Economics,</journal>
    <date>1981</date>
    <note>(in press).</note>
    <author>Commins,B. T., and R. E. Waller.</author>
    <title>Observations from a ten-year study of pollution at a site in the city of London.</title>
    <journal>Atmos. Environ.</journal>
    <volume>1:49-68,</volume>
    <date>1967.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Cralley, L. V.</author>
    <title>The effect of irritant gases upon the rate of ciliary activity.</title>
    <journal>J. Ind. Hyg. and Toxicol.</journal>
    <volume>24:193-198,</volume>
    <date>1942.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>D1</citation-number>
    <author>Alfonso, D. A.</author>
    <title>The Limiting Factors of Nasal Respiration.</title>
    <genre>Ph.D. Thesis,</genre>
    <publisher>University of California,</publisher>
    <location>Santa Barbara,</location>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Drake, R. L., and S. M. Barrager.</author>
    <title>Mathematical Models for Atmospheric Pollutants:</title>
    <genre>Final Report. EA-1131,</genre>
    <publisher>Electric Power Research Institute,</publisher>
    <location>Pala Alto, CA,</location>
    <date>August 1979.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Dreisinger, R. B., and P. C. McGovern.</author>
    <title>Monitoring atmospheric sulfur dioxide and correlating its effects on crops and forests in the Sudbury area:</title>
    <container-title>In: Impact of Air Pollution on Vegetation Conference, Air Pollution Control Association and others,</container-title>
    <location>Toronto, Ontario, Canada,</location>
    <date>April 7-9, 1970.</date>
    <publisher>Air Pollution Control Association,</publisher>
    <location>Pittsburgh, PA,</location>
    <date>1970.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Fenters, J. 0., J. N. Bradof, C. Aranyi, K. Ketels, R. Ehrlich, and D. E. Gardner.</author>
    <title>Health effects of long-term inhalation of sulfuric acid mist - carbon particle mixtures.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Res.</journal>
    <volume>19:244-257,</volume>
    <date>1979.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Ferris, B. G., Jr., H. Chen, S. Puleo, and R. L. H. Murphy, Jr.</author>
    <title>Chronic non-specific respiratory disease in</title>
    <location>Berlin, NewHampshire,</location>
    <date>1967-1973.</date>
    <title>A further follow-up study.</title>
    <journal>Am. Rev. Respir. Dis.</journal>
    <volume>113:475-485,</volume>
    <date>1976.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Ferris, B. G., Jr., I. T. T. Higgins, M. W. Higgins, and J. M. Peters.</author>
    <title>Chronic non-specific respiratory disease in</title>
    <location>Berlin, New Hampshire,</location>
    <date>1961-67.</date>
    <title>A follow-up study.</title>
    <journal>Am. Rev. Respir. Dis.</journal>
    <volume>107:110-122,</volume>
    <date>1973.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Fishchl, M. A., A. Pitchenik, and L. B. Gardner.</author>
    <title>An index ·predicting relapse and need for hospitalization in patients with acute bronchial asthma.</title>
    <journal>N. Engl. J. Med.</journal>
    <volume>305:783-789,</volume>
    <date>1981.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Frank, N. R., M.</author>
    <citation-number>0.</citation-number>
    <author>Amdur, and J. L. Whittenberger.</author>
    <title>A comparison of the acute effects of S02 administered alone or in combination with NaCl particles on the respiratory mechanics of healthy adults.</title>
    <journal>Int. J. Air Water Pollut.</journal>
    <volume>~:125-133,</volume>
    <date>1964.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Frank, N. R., M.</author>
    <citation-number>0.</citation-number>
    <author>Amdur, J. Worcester, and J. L. Whittenberger.</author>
    <title>Effects of acute controlled exposure to S02 on respiratory mechanics in healthy male adults.</title>
    <journal>J. Appl. Physiol.</journal>
    <volume>17:252-258,</volume>
    <date>1962.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Frank, R., C. E. McJilton, and R. J. Charlson.</author>
    <title>Sulfur oxides and particles; effects on pulmo~ nary physiology in man and animals.</title>
    <container-title>In: Proceedings of Conference on Health Effects of Air Pollution. National Academyof Sciences,</container-title>
    <location>Washington, DC, Ocotber 3-5,</location>
    <date>1973.</date>
    <note>Serial No. 93-15, U.S. Senate, Committee on Public Works,</note>
    <location>Washington, DC,</location>
    <date>1973,</date>
    <pages>pp. 207-225.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Franklin, W.</author>
    <title>Asthma in the emergency room.</title>
    <journal>Assessment and treatment. N. Engl. J. Med.</journal>
    <volume>305:826-827,</volume>
    <date>1981.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <pages>- '</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Gardner, D. E., F. J. Miller, J. W. Illing, and J. M. Kirtz.</author>
    <title>Increased infectivity with exposure to ozone and sulfuric acid.</title>
    <journal>Toxicol. Lett.</journal>
    <volume>!:59-64,</volume>
    <pages>1977a.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Gardner, D. E., F. J. Miller, J. W. Illing, and J. M. Kirtz.</author>
    <title>Alterations in bacterial defense mechanisms of the lung induced by inhalation of cadmium.</title>
    <journal>Bull. Eur. Physiopathol. Respir.</journal>
    <volume>13:157-174,</volume>
    <pages>1977b.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Giddens, W. E., and G. A. Fairchild.</author>
    <title>Effects of sulfur dioxide on the nasal mucosa of mice.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>25:166-173,</volume>
    <date>1972.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Glasser, M., L. Greenburg, and F. Field.</author>
    <title>Mortality and morbidity during a period of high levels of air pollution,</title>
    <location>New York,</location>
    <date>November 23-25, 1966.</date>
    <title>Arch.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>15:684-694,</volume>
    <date>1967.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Greenberg, L., M. Jacobs, B. Drolette, F. Field, and M. Braverman.</author>
    <title>Report of an air pollution incident in NewYork City,</title>
    <date>November, 1953.</date>
    <title>Pub.</title>
    <journal>Health Rep.</journal>
    <volume>77:</volume>
    <pages>7-16,</pages>
    <date>1962.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Greenburg, L., F. Field, C. Erhardt, M. Glasser, and J. Reed.</author>
    <title>Air pollution, influenza, and mortality in NewYork City.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>15:430-438,</volume>
    <date>1967.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Groblicki, P. J., G. T. Wolf, and R. J. Countess.</author>
    <title>Visibility Reducing Species in the Denver 11 Brown Cloud,11 Part I, Relationships Between Extinction and Chemical Composition.</title>
    <journal>General Motors Research Laboratories publication</journal>
    <volume>#GMR-2417,Env #81,</volume>
    <location>Warren, MI,</location>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Grose, E. C., D. E. Gardner, and F. J. Miller.</author>
    <title>Response of ciliated epithelium to ozone and sulfuric acid.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Res.</journal>
    <volume>22:377-385,</volume>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Hatch, T. E., and P. Gross.</author>
    <title>Pulmonary Deposition and Retention of Inhaled Aerosols.</title>
    <publisher>Academic Press,</publisher>
    <location>NewYork, NY,</location>
    <date>1964.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Haynie, F. H.</author>
    <title>Theoretical air pollution and climate effects on materials confirmed by zinc corrosion data.</title>
    <container-title>In: Durability of Building Materials and Components.</container-title>
    <editor>P. J. Sereda and G. G. Levitan, edS:-,</editor>
    <genre>ASTM Special Technical Publication 691,</genre>
    <publisher>American Society for Testing and Materials,</publisher>
    <location>Philadelphia, PA,</location>
    <date>1980,</date>
    <pages>pp. 157-175.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Haynie, F. H., and J. B. Upham.</author>
    <title>Correlation between corrosion behavior of steel and atmospheric pollution data.</title>
    <container-title>In: Corrosion in Natural Environments. ASTMSpecial Technical Publication 558,</container-title>
    <publisher>AmerTcanSociety for Testing and Materials,</publisher>
    <location>Philadelphia, PA,</location>
    <date>1974,</date>
    <pages>pp. 33-51.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Haynie, F. H., and J. B. Upham.</author>
    <title>Effects of atmospheric sulfur dioxide on the corrosion of zinc.</title>
    <journal>Mater. Prot. Perform.</journal>
    <volume>2:35-40,</volume>
    <date>1970.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Haynie, F. H., J. W. Spence, and J. B. Upham.</author>
    <title>Effects of gaseous pollutants on materials--a chamber study.</title>
    <container-title>EPA-600/3-76-015, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency,</container-title>
    <location>Research Triangle Park, NC, February,</location>
    <date>1976.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Hazucha, M., and D. V. Bates.</author>
    <title>Combinedeffect of ozone and sulphur dioxide on humanpulmonary function.</title>
    <journal>Nature (London)</journal>
    <volume>257:50-51,</volume>
    <date>1975.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Heck, W. W., and C. S. Brandt.</author>
    <title>Effects on vegetation: native, crops, forest.</title>
    <container-title>In: Air Pollution.</container-title>
    <editor>A. C. Stern, ed.,</editor>
    <publisher>Academic Press,</publisher>
    <location>NewYork, NY,</location>
    <date>1977,</date>
    <pages>pp. 157-229.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Hill, A. B.</author>
    <title>The environment and diseases: associations or causation?</title>
    <journal>In: Pro. R. Soc. Med.</journal>
    <volume>55:295-300,</volume>
    <date>1965.</date>
    <pages>1-109</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Hill, A. C., S. Hill, C. Lamb, and T. W. Barrett.</author>
    <title>Sensitivity of native desert vegetation to so2 and to so2 and ND2 combined.</title>
    <journal>J. Air Pollut. Control Assoc.</journal>
    <volume>24:153-157,</volume>
    <date>1974.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Holland, W. W., A. E. Bennett, I. R. Cameron, C. du V. Florey, S. R. Leeder, R. S. F. Schilling, A. V. Swan, and R. E. Waller.</author>
    <title>Health effects of particulate pollution: Re-appraising the evidence.</title>
    <journal>Am. J. Epidemiol.</journal>
    <volume>llQ.(5):</volume>
    <pages>525-659,</pages>
    <date>1979.</date>
    <editor>• Horvath, H., and K. E. Noll.</editor>
    <title>The relationship between atmospheric light scattering co-efficient and visibility.</title>
    <journal>Atmos. Environ.</journal>
    <volume>1:543-550,</volume>
    <date>1969.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Horvath, S. M., and L. J. Folinsbee.</author>
    <title>Interactions of two air pollutants, sulfur dioxide and ozone, on lung functions.</title>
    <container-title>Grant ARB~4-1266,California Air Resources Board,</container-title>
    <location>Sacramento, CA,</location>
    <date>March 1977.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Horvath, S. M., L. J. Folinsbee, and J. F. Bedi.</author>
    <title>Effects of large (0.9 µm) sulfuric acid aerosols on humanpulmonary function.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Res.,</journal>
    <date>1981</date>
    <note>(in press).</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Husar, R. B., D. E. Patterson, J. M. Holloway, W. E. Wilson, and T. G. Ellestad.</author>
    <title>Trends of eastern U.S. haziness since 1948.</title>
    <container-title>In: Proceedings of the Fourth Symposium on Atmospheric Turbulence, Diffusion, and Air Pollution,</container-title>
    <publisher>American Meterorological Society,</publisher>
    <location>Reno, Nevada,</location>
    <date>January 15-18, 1979.</date>
    <publisher>American Meteorological Society,</publisher>
    <location>Boston,</location>
    <volume>MA,1~79,</volume>
    <pages>pp. 249-256.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>International Standards Organization.</author>
    <title>Size definitions for particle sampling: Recommendations of ad hoc working group appointed by TC 146 of the International Standar~s Organization.</title>
    <journal>Am. Ind. Hyg. Assoc. J.</journal>
    <volume>42:A64-A68,</volume>
    <date>1981.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Islam, M. S., and W. T. Ulmer.</author>
    <title>The effects of long-time exposure (8 h per day on 4 successive days) to a gas mixture of S02 + N02 + 03 in the threefold MIC range (maximumemission concentration) on lung function and reactivity of the bronchial system of healthy persons.</title>
    <journal>Wissenschaft und Umwelt1:186-190,</journal>
    <date>1979(b).</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Islam, M. S., and W. T. Ulmer.</author>
    <title>The influence of acute exposure against a combination of 5.0 ppm S02 , 5.0 ppm</title>
    <volume>N02 , and 0. 1</volume>
    <note>ppm 03 on the lung function in the MAK (lower toxic limit) area (short-time test). Wissenschaft und Umwelt1:131-137, 1979(a).</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Islam, M. S., E. Vastag, and W. T. Ulmer.</author>
    <title>Sulphur-dioxide induced bronchial hyperreactivity against acetylcholine.</title>
    <journal>Int. Arch. Arbeitsmed.</journal>
    <volume>29:221-232,</volume>
    <date>1972.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Jaeger, M. J., D. Tribble, and H. J. Wittig.</author>
    <title>Effect of 0.5 ppm sulfur dioxide on the respiratory function of normal and asthmatic subjects.</title>
    <journal>Lung</journal>
    <volume>156:119-127,</volume>
    <date>1979.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Kagawa,J., and K. Tsuru.</author>
    <title>Respiratory effect of 2-hour exposure with intermittent exercise to ozone and sulfur dioxide alone and in combination in normal subjects.</title>
    <journal>Jap. J. Hyg.</journal>
    <volume>34:690-696,</volume>
    <date>1979.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Kerr, H. D., T. J. Kulle, B. P. Farrell, L. R. Sauder, J. L. Young, D. L. Swift, and R. M. Borushok.</author>
    <title>Effects of sulfuric acid aerosol on pulmonary function in humansubjects: an environmental chamber study.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Res:</journal>
    <volume>26:42-50,</volume>
    <date>1981.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Kleinman, M. T., and J. D. Hackney.</author>
    <title>Effects of sulfate aerosols upon human pulmonary function. APRACProject CAPM-27-75,Coordinating Research Council,</title>
    <publisher>Inc.,</publisher>
    <location>NewYork, NY,</location>
    <date>1978.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Kleinman, M. T., R. M. Bailey, Y. C. Chang, K. W. Clark, M. P. Jones, W. S. .Linn, and J. D. Hackney.</author>
    <title>Exposures of human vo,lunteers to a contro 11ed atmospheric mixture of ozone, sulfur dioxide and sulfuric acid.</title>
    <journal>Am. Indus. Hyg. Assoc. J.</journal>
    <volume>42:61-69,</volume>
    <date>1981.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Koenig, J. Q., W. E. Pierson, and R. Frank.</author>
    <title>Acute effects of inhaled S02 plus NaCl droplet aerosol on pulmonary function in asthmatic adolescents.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Res.</journal>
    <volume>22:145-153,</volume>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Koenig, J. Q., W. E. Pierson, M. Horike, and R. Frank.</author>
    <title>Effects of S02 plus NaCl aerosol combined with moderate exercise on pulmonary function in asthmatic adolescents.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Res.</journal>
    <volume>25:340-348,</volume>
    <pages>~81.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Kreisman, H., C. A. Mitchell, H. R. Hosein, and A.</author>
    <title>8ounuys. Effect of low concentrations of sulfur dioxide on respiratory function in man.</title>
    <journal>Lung</journal>
    <volume>154:25-34,</volume>
    <date>1976.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Last, J. A., and C. E. Cross.</author>
    <title>A new model for health effects of air pollutants: evidence for synergistic effects of mixtures of ozone and sulfuric acid aerosols on rat lungs.</title>
    <journal>J. Lab. Clin. Med.</journal>
    <volume>91:328-339,</volume>
    <date>1978.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Lave, L.</author>
    <title>8., and 8.</title>
    <author>P. Seskin.</author>
    <title>Air pollution and human health.</title>
    <journal>Science</journal>
    <volume>169:732-733,</volume>
    <date>1970.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Lave, L.</author>
    <volume>8.,</volume>
    <pages>and 8.</pages>
    <author>P. Seskin.</author>
    <title>Air pollution, climate, and home heating: Their effects on U.S. mortality rate.</title>
    <journal>Am.J. Pub. Health</journal>
    <volume>62:909-916,</volume>
    <date>1972.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Lave, L.</author>
    <title>8., and 8.</title>
    <author>P. Seskin.</author>
    <title>Air Pollution and HumanHealth.</title>
    <publisher>The Johns Hopkins University Press,</publisher>
    <location>Baltimore,</location>
    <date>MD,1977.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Lawther, P. J.</author>
    <title>Effects of inhalation of sulfur dioxide on respiration and pulse rates in normal subjects.</title>
    <journal>Lancet</journal>
    <volume>l:745-748,</volume>
    <date>1955.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Lawther, P. J.</author>
    <title>Climate, air pollution and chronic bronchitis.</title>
    <journal>Proc. R. Soc. Med.</journal>
    <volume>51:262-264,</volume>
    <date>1958.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Lawther, P. J., A. J. Macfarlane, R. E. Waller, and A. G·.F. Brooks.</author>
    <title>Pulmonary function and sulphur dioxide, some preliminary findings.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Res.</journal>
    <volume>10:355-367,</volume>
    <date>1975.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Lawther, P. J., R. E. Waller, and M. Henderson.</author>
    <title>Air pollution and exacerbations of bronchitis.</title>
    <journal>Thorax</journal>
    <volume>25:525-539,</volume>
    <date>1970.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Lebowitz, M. D., E. J. Cassell, and J. D. Mccarroll.</author>
    <title>Health and the urban environment. XV. Acute respiratory episodes as reactions by sensitive individuals to air pollution and weather.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Res.</journal>
    <volume>~:(2):135-141,</volume>
    <date>1972.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Lee, R. E. Jr., J. S. Caldwell, and G. B. Morgan.</author>
    <title>The evaluation of methods for measuring suspended particulates in air.</title>
    <journal>Atmos. Environ.</journal>
    <volume>£:593-622,</volume>
    <date>1972.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Leikauf, G., D. B. Yeates, K. A. Wales, D. Spedtor, R. E. Albert, and M. Lippmann.</author>
    <title>Effects of sulfuric acid aerosol on respiratory mechanics and mucociliary particle clearance in healthy nonsmoking adults.</title>
    <journal>Am. Ind. Hyg. Assoc. J.</journal>
    <volume>42:27~-282,</volume>
    <date>1981.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Lewis, T. R., D. E. Campbell, and T. R. Vaught, Jr.</author>
    <title>Effects on canine pulmonary function via induced N02 impairment, particulate interaction and subsequent sax.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>18:596-601,</volume>
    <date>1969.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Lewis, T. R., W. J. Moorman, W. F. Ludmann, and K. I. Campbell.</author>
    <title>Toxicity of long-term . exposure to oxides of sulfur.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>26:16-21,</volume>
    <date>1973.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Linn, W. S., R. M. Bailey, D. A. Medway,J. G. Venet, L. H. Wightman, and J. D. Hackney.</author>
    <title>Respiratory responses of young adult asthmatics to sulfur dioxide exposure under simulated ambient conditions.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Res.,</journal>
    <volume>1982,</volume>
    <date>(in press).</date>
    <author>•Linn, W. S., M. P. Jones, R. M. Bailey, M. T. Kleinman, C. E. Spier, R. D. Fischer, and J. D. Hackney.</author>
    <title>Respiratory effects of mixed nitrogen dioxide and sulfur dioxide in human volunteers under simulated ambient exposure conditions.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Res.</journal>
    <volume>22:431-438,</volume>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Lippmann, M.</author>
    <title>Regional deposition of particles in the humanrespiratory tract.</title>
    <container-title>In: Handbook of Physiology, Section 9: Reactions to Environmental Agents.</container-title>
    <editor>D. H. K. Lee, H. L. Falk, and S. D. Murphy, eds.,</editor>
    <container-title>The American Physiological Society,</container-title>
    <location>Bethesda, MD,</location>
    <date>1977,</date>
    <pages>pp. 213-232.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Lunn, J. E., J. Knowelden, and A. J. Handyside.</author>
    <title>Patterns of respiratory illness in Sheffield infant schoolchildren.</title>
    <journal>Br. J. Prev. Soc. Med.</journal>
    <volume>21:7-16,</volume>
    <date>1967.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Lunn, J. E., J. Knowelden, and J. W. Roe.</author>
    <title>Patterns of respiratory illness in Sheffield junior schoolchildren. A follow-up study.</title>
    <journal>Br. J. Prev. Soc. Med.</journal>
    <volume>24:223-228,</volume>
    <date>1970.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Macias, E. S., R. B. Husar, and J. D. Husar.</author>
    <title>Monitoring of atmospheric aerosol mass and sulfur concentration.</title>
    <container-title>In: International Conference on Environmental Sensing and Assessment, Volume1, World Health Organization and Others, Las Vegas,</container-title>
    <location>Nevada,</location>
    <date>September 14-19, 1975.</date>
    <publisher>Institute of Electrical &amp; Electronics Engineers, Inc.,</publisher>
    <location>NewYork, NY,</location>
    <date>1976.</date>
    <pages>paper 5-2.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Martin, A. E.</author>
    <title>Mortality and morbidity statistics and air pollution.</title>
    <journal>Proc. Roy. Soc. Med.</journal>
    <volume>57:969-975,</volume>
    <date>1964.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Martin, A. E., and W. H. Bradley.</author>
    <title>Mortality, fog and atmospheric pollution--An investigation during the winter of 1958-59.</title>
    <journal>Mon. Bull. Minist. Health, Public Health Lab. Serv.</journal>
    <volume>19:56-72,</volume>
    <date>1960.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Mazumdar, S., H. Schimmel, and I. Higgins.</author>
    <title>Daily mortality, smoke, and 502 in London, England, 1959-1972.</title>
    <container-title>Proceedings of APCAConference on the Proposed S02 and Particulate Standard, Sept.</container-title>
    <pages>16-18,</pages>
    <date>1980,</date>
    <location>Pittsburgh, PA,</location>
    <date>1981,</date>
    <pages>pp. 219-239.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Mccarroll, J. R., and W. H. Bradley.</author>
    <title>Excess-mortality as an indicator of health effects of air pollution.</title>
    <journal>Am. J. Pub. Health</journal>
    <volume>56:1933-1942,</volume>
    <date>1966..</date>
    <author>McDermott, M.</author>
    <title>Acute respiratory effects of the inhalation of coal-dust particles.</title>
    <journal>J. Physiol.</journal>
    <volume>162:53,</volume>
    <date>1962.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>McFarland, A. R., C. A. Ortiz, and C. E. Rodes.</author>
    <title>Wind tunnel evaluation of the British smoke shade sampler.</title>
    <journal>Atmos. Environ.</journal>
    <volume>16:325-328,</volume>
    <date>1982.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>McJilton, C., R. Frank, and R. Charlson.</author>
    <title>Role of relative humidity in the synergistic effect of a sulfur dioxide-aerosol mixture on the lung.</title>
    <journal>Science</journal>
    <volume>182:503-504,</volume>
    <date>1973.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Melville, G. N.</author>
    <title>Changes in specific airway conductance in healthy volunteers following nasal and oral inhalation of so2.</title>
    <journal>West Indian Med. J.</journal>
    <volume>19:321~235,</volume>
    <date>1970.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Miller, K., and H. W. DeKoning.</author>
    <title>Particle sizing instrumentation.</title>
    <container-title>Paper presented at 67th Annual APCAmeeting,</container-title>
    <location>Denver, CO,</location>
    <date>June 9, 1974,</date>
    <pages>Paper #74-48.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Morrow, P. E., D. V. Pates, B. R. Fish, T. F. Hatch, and T. T. Mercer.</author>
    <title>International commission on radiological protection task group on lung dynamics, deposition and retention models for internal dosimetry of the human respiratory tract.</title>
    <journal>Health Phys.</journal>
    <volume>12:173-207,</volume>
    <date>1966.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Mulholland, G. W., D. Y. H. Pui, A. Kapadia, and B: Y. H. Liu.</author>
    <title>Aerosol number and mass concentration measurements: A comparison of the EAAwith other measurement techniques.</title>
    <journal>J. Colloid Interface Sci.</journal>
    <volume>77(1):57-67,</volume>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Nadel, J., H. Salem, B. Tamplin, and Y. Tokiwa.</author>
    <title>Mechanismof bronchoconstriction during inhalation of sulfur dioxide.</title>
    <journal>J. Appl. Physiol.</journal>
    <volume>20:164-167,</volume>
    <date>1965.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Nakamura, K.</author>
    <title>Response of pulmunary airway resistance by interaction of aerosols and gases in different physical and chemical nature.</title>
    <journal>Nippon Eiseigaku Zasshi</journal>
    <volume>19:38-50,</volume>
    <date>1964.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <title>National Air Pollution Control Administration. Air Quality Criteria for Particulate Matter.</title>
    <publisher>AP-49, U. S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare,</publisher>
    <location>Washington, DC,</location>
    <date>January 1969.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <title>National Air Pollution Control Administration. Air Quality Criteria for Sulfur Oxides.</title>
    <container-title>AP-50, U.S. Department of Health Education, and Welfare,</container-title>
    <location>Washington, DC,</location>
    <date>April 1970.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Newhouse, M. T., M. Dolovich, G. Obminski, and R. K. Wolff.</author>
    <title>Effect of TLVlevels of S02 and H2so4 on bronchial clearance in exercising man.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>33:24-32,</volume>
    <date>1978.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Niinimaa, V., P. Cole, S. Mintz, and R. J. Shephard.</author>
    <title>Oronasal distribution of respiratory flow.</title>
    <journal>Resp. Physiol.</journal>
    <volume>43:69-75,</volume>
    <date>1981.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Niinimaa, V., P. Cole, S. Mintz, and R. J. Shephard.</author>
    <title>The switching point from nasal to oronasal breathing.</title>
    <journal>Resp. Physiol.</journal>
    <volume>42:61-71,</volume>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <editor>Orenstein, A. J., Ed.</editor>
    <container-title>Proceedings of the Pneumonoconiosis Conference, Ministry of Mines,</container-title>
    <location>Johannesburg,</location>
    <publisher>South Africa,</publisher>
    <date>1959.</date>
    <publisher>J &amp;A Churchill, Ltd.,</publisher>
    <location>London, England,</location>
    <date>1960.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Pace, T. G., J. G. Watson, and C. E. Rodes.</author>
    <title>Prel,iminary interpretations of inhalable particulate network data.</title>
    <container-title>Presented at the 74th Annual Meeting of the Air Pollution Control Association,</container-title>
    <location>Philadelphia, PA,</location>
    <date>1981,</date>
    <pages>Paper #81-5.2.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Raabe, 0. G.</author>
    <title>Deposition and clearance of inhaled aerosols.</title>
    <publisher>U.S. Department of Energy. National Technical Information Service,</publisher>
    <location>UCD-472-503,Springfield, VA,</location>
    <date>1979.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Regan, G. F., S. K. Goranson, and L. L. Larson.</author>
    <title>Use of tape samplers as fine particulate monitors.</title>
    <journal>J. Air Pollut. Control Assoc.</journal>
    <volume>29:1158-1160,</volume>
    <date>1979.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Reichel, G.</author>
    <title>The effect of sulfur dioxide on the airway resistance of man.</title>
    <container-title>Presented at the 12th Annual Meeting,</container-title>
    <publisher>German Society for Industrial Medicine,</publisher>
    <location>Dortmund, Germany,</location>
    <date>October 25-28, 1972.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Sackner, M. A., D. Ford, R. Fernandez, J. Cipley, D. Perez, M. Kwocka, M. Reinhart, E. D. Michaelson, R. Schreck, and A. Wanner.</author>
    <title>Effects of sulfuric acid aerosol on cardiopulmonary function of dogs, sheep and humans.</title>
    <journal>Am. Rev. Respir. Dis.</journal>
    <volume>118:497-510,</volume>
    <date>1978.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Schiff, L. J., M. M. Bryne, J. D. Fenters, J. A. Graham, and D. E. Gardner.</author>
    <title>Cytotoxic effects of sulfuric acid mist, carbon particulates, and their mixtures on hamster tracheal epithelium.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Res.</journal>
    <volume>19:339-354,</volume>
    <date>1979.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Schlesinger, R. B., M. Halpern, R. E. Albert, and M. Lippmann.</author>
    <title>Effect of chronic inhalation of sulfuric acid mist upon mucociliary clearance from the lungs of donkeys.</title>
    <journal>J. Environ. Pathol. Toxicol.</journal>
    <volume>~:1351-1367,</volume>
    <date>1979.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Schlesinger, R. B., M. Lippmann, and R. E. Albert.</author>
    <title>Effects of short-term exposures to sulfuric acid and ammoniumsulfate aerosols upon bronchial airways function in donkeys.</title>
    <journal>Am. Ind. Hyg. Assoc. J.</journal>
    <volume>39:275-286,</volume>
    <date>1978.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Sheppard, D., A. Saisho, J. A. Nadel, and H. A. Boushey.</author>
    <title>Exercise increases sulfur dioxideinduced bronchoconstriction in asthmatic subjects.</title>
    <journal>Am. Rev. Resp. Dis.,</journal>
    <date>1981</date>
    <note>(in press).</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Sheppard, D., W. S. Wong, C. F. Uehara, J. A. Nadel, and H. A. Boushey.</author>
    <title>Lower threshold and greater bronchomotor responsiveness of asthmatic subjects to sulfur dioxide.</title>
    <journal>Am. Rev. Respir. Dis.</journal>
    <volume>122:873-878,</volume>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Sim, V. M., and R. E. Pattle.</author>
    <title>Effect of possible smog irritants on human subjects.</title>
    <journal>J. Am. Med. Assoc.</journal>
    <volume>165:1908-1913,</volume>
    <date>1957.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Slinn, W. G. N.</author>
    <title>Dry deposition and resuspension of aerosol particles: a new look at some old problems.</title>
    <container-title>In: Atmosphere-Surface Exchange of Particulate and Gaseous Pollutants (1974), Proceedings of a Symposium, Battel'le Pacific Northwest Laboratories and U.S. Atomic Energy Commission,</container-title>
    <location>Richland, Washington,</location>
    <date>September 4-6, 1974,</date>
    <genre>ERDASymposiumSeries 38,</genre>
    <publisher>Energy Research and Development Administration,</publisher>
    <location>Oak Ridge, TN,</location>
    <date>January 1976,</date>
    <pages>pp. 1-40.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Smith, R. L.</author>
    <title>Ecology and Field Biology.</title>
    <edition>3rd Ed.,</edition>
    <publisher>Harper and Row,</publisher>
    <location>NewYork, NY,</location>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Snell, R. E., and P. C. Luchsinger.</author>
    <title>Effects of sulfur dioxide on expiratory flow rates and total respiratory resistance in normal humansubjects.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>18:693-698,</volume>
    <date>1969.</date>
    <author>-Speizer, F. E., and N. R. Frank.</author>
    <title>A comparison of changes in pulmonary flow resistance in health volunteers acutely exposed to so2 by mouth and by nose.</title>
    <journal>Br. J. Ind; Med.</journal>
    <volume>23:75-79,</volume>
    <date>1966.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Spence, J. W., F. H. Haynie, and J. B. Upham.</author>
    <title>Effects of gaseous pollutants on paints: a chamber study.</title>
    <journal>J. Paint Technol.</journal>
    <volume>47:57-63,</volume>
    <date>1975.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Stacy, R. W., M. Friedman, J. Green, D. E. House, L. Raggio, L. J. Roger and M. Hazucha.</author>
    <title>Effects of 0.75 ppm sulfur dioxide on pulmonary function parameters of normal humansubjects.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health,</journal>
    <date>1981</date>
    <note>(in press).</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Threshold Limits Committee.</author>
    <title>Threshold limit values of airborne contaminants for 1968.</title>
    <container-title>American Conference of Governmental and Industrial Hygienists,</container-title>
    <location>Cincinnati, OH,</location>
    <date>1968.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Tomono,Y.</author>
    <title>Effect~ of so2 on hu~an pulmonary functions.</title>
    <journal>Sangyo Igaku</journal>
    <volume>~:77-85,</volume>
    <date>1961.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Toyama, T.</author>
    <title>Studies on aerosols. Synergistic response of the pulmonary airway resistance of inhaling sodium chloride aerosols and so2 in man.</title>
    <journal>Sangyo Igaku</journal>
    <volume>1:86-92,</volume>
    <date>1962.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Toyama, T., and K. Nakamura.</author>
    <title>Synergistic response to hydrogen peroxide aerosols and sulfur dioxide to pulmonary airway resistance.</title>
    <journal>Ind. Health~:</journal>
    <pages>34-45,</pages>
    <date>1964.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Trijonis, J., and R. Shapland.</author>
    <title>Existing Visibility Levels in the U.S.:</title>
    <container-title>Isopleth Maps of Visibility in Suburban/Nonurban Areas During 1974-1976. EPA-450/5-79-010, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency,</container-title>
    <location>Research Triangle Park, NC,</location>
    <date>1979.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Trijonis, J., J. Eldon, J. Gins, and G. Berglund.</author>
    <title>Analysis of the St.</title>
    <container-title>Louis RAMS Ambient Particulate Data.</container-title>
    <volume>Vol. I</volume>
    <container-title>- Final Report. EPA-450/4-80-006a, U.S. Environmental Protection - Agency,</container-title>
    <location>Research Triangle Park, NC,</location>
    <date>February 1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare.</author>
    <title>Air Quality Criteria for Particulate Matter.</title>
    <location>Washington, DC,</location>
    <author>U.S. Government Printing Office,</author>
    <date>1969.</date>
    <pages>211 pp.</pages>
    <publisher>National Air Pollution Control Administration Publication No. AP-49.</publisher>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency.</author>
    <title>Air Quality Criteria for Lead.</title>
    <container-title>EPA-600/8-77-017, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Office of Research and Development,</container-title>
    <location>Research Triangle Park, NC, December1977.</location>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency.</author>
    <title>Air Quality Criteria for Oxides of Nitrogen.</title>
    <journal>Draft Final.</journal>
    <volume>EPA-600/8:82-026,</volume>
    <author>U. S.</author>
    <title>Environmental Protection Agency,</title>
    <location>Research Triangle Park, NC,</location>
    <date>September, 1982.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>U.S. Environmental Protectfon Agency.</author>
    <title>EPA Report fo Congress: Protecting Visibility.</title>
    <container-title>EPA-450/5-79-008, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency,</container-title>
    <location>Research Triangle Park, NC,</location>
    <date>1979.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency.</author>
    <title>National Air .Pollutant Emission Estimates,</title>
    <date>1940-1976.</date>
    <title>EPA-450/1-78-003, U.</title>
    <container-title>S. Environmental Protect ion Agency, Office · of Air Qua1i ty Planning and Standards,</container-title>
    <location>Research Triangle Park, NC,</location>
    <date>July 1978.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency.</author>
    <title>National Air Pollutant Emissions Estimates,</title>
    <date>1970-1978.</date>
    <title>EPA-450/4-80-002, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Office of Air Quality Planning and Standards, Research Triangle Park,</title>
    <location>NC,</location>
    <date>January 1980.</date>
    <title>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. Sulfur dioxide one-hour values, National Aerometric Data Bank Computer Report for July 1979, Monitoring and Data Analysis Division, Office of Air Quality Planning and Standards, U.S.</title>
    <journal>Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park,</journal>
    <note>NC, 1981 (unpublished). U.S. Senate. Committee on Public Works, U.S.</note>
    <publisher>Government Printing Office,</publisher>
    <location>Washington, DC,</location>
    <date>1968.</date>
    <note>Air Quality Criteria Staff Report, 90th Congress, 2d Session, 1968.</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>U.S. Surgeon General.</author>
    <title>Smoking and Health: Report of the Advisory Committee to the Surgeon General of the Public Health Service.</title>
    <container-title>PHS Pub. No. 1103, U.S. Dept. of Health, Education, and Welfare,</container-title>
    <location>Washington, DC,</location>
    <date>1964.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Utell, M. J., A. T. Aquilina, W. J. Hall, D. M. Speers, R. G. Douglas Jr., F. R. Gibb, P. E. - Morrow, and R. W. White.</author>
    <title>Development of airway reactivity to nitrates in subjects with influenza.</title>
    <journal>Amer. Rev. Respir. Dis.</journal>
    <volume>121:233-241,</volume>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Utell, M. J., P. E. Morrow, and R. W. Hyde.</author>
    <title>Inhaled Particles.</title>
    <container-title>V. Proceedings of the 5th International Symposium,</container-title>
    <location>Cardiff, Wales,</location>
    <date>September 1980,</date>
    <publisher>Pergamon Press,</publisher>
    <location>London, England,</location>
    <date>1981</date>
    <note>(in press).</note>
    <author>von Nieding, G., H. M. Wagner, H. Krekeler, H. Lollgen, W. Fries, and A. Beuthan.</author>
    <title>Controlled studies of human exposure to single and combined action of N02 , o3 and so2.</title>
    <journal>Int. Arch. Occup. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>43:195-210,</volume>
    <date>1979.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Waggoner, A. P., and R. E. Weiss.</author>
    <title>Comparison of fine particle mass concentration and light scattering in ambient aerosol.</title>
    <journal>Atmos. Env.</journal>
    <volume>14:623-626,</volume>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Waller, R. E.</author>
    <title>Experiments on the calibration of smoke filters.</title>
    <journal>J. Air Pollut. Control Assoc.</journal>
    <volume>14:323-335,</volume>
    <date>1964.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Ware, J. H., L. A. Thibodeau, F. E. Speizer, S. Colome, and B. G. Ferris, Jr.</author>
    <title>Assessment of the health effects of atmospheric sulfur oxides and particulate matter: Evidence from observational studies.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Health Perspect.,</journal>
    <date>1981</date>
    <note>(in press).</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Wedding, J. B., M. Weigand, W. John, and S. Wall.</author>
    <title>Sampling effectiveness of the inlet to the dichotomous sampler.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Sci. Technol.</journal>
    <volume>14:1367-1370,</volume>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Weir, F. W., and P. A. Bromberg.</author>
    <title>Further investigation of the effects of sulfur dioxide on human subjects.</title>
    <genre>Annual Report Project No. CAWCS-15,</genre>
    <publisher>American Petroleum Institute,</publisher>
    <location>Washington, DC,</location>
    <date>1972.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Winkelstein, W.</author>
    <title>Utility or futility of ordinary mortality statistics in the study of air pollution effects.</title>
    <container-title>In: Proceedings of the Sixth Berkeley Symposium on Mathematical Statistics and Probability.</container-title>
    <editor>L. LeCam, J. Newyman,and E. Scott, eds.,</editor>
    <publisher>University of California Press,</publisher>
    <location>Berkeley, CA,</location>
    <date>1972,</date>
    <pages>pp.539-554.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Winkelstein, W., and M. Gay.</author>
    <title>Suspended particulate air pollution. Relationship to mortality from cirrhosis of the liver.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>22:174-177,</volume>
    <date>1971.</date>
    <note>•</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Winkelstein, W., and S. Kantor.</author>
    <title>Stomach cancer.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>14:544-547,</volume>
    <date>1967.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Winkelstein, W., S. Kantor, E. Davis, C. Maneri, and W. Mosher.</author>
    <title>The relationship of air pollution and economic status to total mortality and selected respiratory system mortality in men.</title>
    <journal>I. Suspended particulates. Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>14:162-170,</volume>
    <date>1967.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Wisniewski, J., and E. L. Keitz.</author>
    <title>Acid rain deposition patterns in the continental United States.</title>
    <journal>Water, Air Soil Pollut.,</journal>
    <date>1981</date>
    <note>(in press).</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Wolff, R. K., B. A. Muggenburg,and S. A. Silbaugh.</author>
    <title>Effects of sulfuric acid mist on tracheal mucous clearance in awake beagle dogs.</title>
    <journal>Am:--'Rev.Respir. Dis.</journal>
    <volume>119:242,</volume>
    <date>1979.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Wolff, R. K., M. Dolovich, C. M. Rossman, and M. T. Newhouse.</author>
    <title>Sulphur dioxide and tracheobronchial clearance in man.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>30:521-527,</volume>
    <pages>1975a.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>Wolff, R. K., M. Dolovich, G. ObQJ.inski,and M. T. Newhouse.</author>
    <title>Effect of sulfur dioxide on tracheobronchial clearance at rest and during exercise.</title>
    <container-title>Inhaled Particles, Proceedings of the 4th International Symposium,Edinburgh,</container-title>
    <location>Scotland,</location>
    <date>September 22-26, 1975.</date>
    <editor>W. H. -Walton, ed.,</editor>
    <location>PergamonPress, London, Engl_and,1975b,</location>
    <pages>pp. 321-332.</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>World Meteorological Organization.</author>
    <title>Atmospheric Turbidity and Precipitation Chemistry Data for the World 1972.</title>
    <publisher>Environmental,Data Service, National Climatic Center,</publisher>
    <location>Asheville, NC,</location>
    <date>1974.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>World Meteorological Organization.</author>
    <title>Atmospheric Turbidity and Precipitation Chemistry Data for the World 1973. Environmental Data Service, National Climatic Center,</title>
    <location>Asheville, NC,</location>
    <date>1975.</date>
    <title>,._____ World Meteorological Organization.</title>
    <container-title>Atmospheric Turbidity and Precipitation Chemistry Data for the World 1974. Environmental Data Service,</container-title>
    <location>National Climatic Center, Asheville, NC,</location>
    <date>1976.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>World Meteorological Organization.</author>
    <title>Global Monitoring of the Environment for Selected Atmospheric Constitµents 1975.</title>
    <publisher>Environmental Data Service, National Climatic Center,</publisher>
    <location>Asheville, NC,</location>
    <date>1977.</date>
    <note>'</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>1.</citation-number>
    <author>Boushey, H.A., Holtsman, M. J., Sheller, J. R., Nadel, J.</author>
    <title>A.: State of the art.</title>
    <journal>Bronchial hyperract~vity. Am. Rev. Respir. Dis.</journal>
    <volume>121:389,</volume>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>2.</citation-number>
    <author>Cole, P., R. Forsyth and J. S. J. Haight.</author>
    <title>Respiratory Resistance of the Oral Airway.</title>
    <journal>Am. Rev. Respir. Dis.</journal>
    <volume>125:</volume>
    <pages>363-365</pages>
    <date>(1982)</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>3.</citation-number>
    <author>Dodge, R. R., and B. Burrows.</author>
    <title>The prevalence and incidence of asthma and asthma-like symptoms in a general population sample.</title>
    <journal>Am. Rev. Respir. Dis.</journal>
    <volume>122:567-575,</volume>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>4.</citation-number>
    <author>Kirkpatrick, M. B., 0; Sheppard, J. A. Nadel, and H. A. Boushey.</author>
    <title>Effect of the oronasal breathing route on sulfur dioxide-induced brochoconstriction in exercising asthmatic subjects.</title>
    <journal>Am. Rev. Respir. Dis.</journal>
    <volume>125:</volume>
    <pages>627-631</pages>
    <date>(1982)</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>5.</citation-number>
    <author>Koenig, J. Q., W. E. Pierson, and R. Frank.</author>
    <title>Acute effects of inhaled so plus NaCl droplet aerosol on pulmonary function in asthmatic adolescents. 2 Environ.</title>
    <journal>Res.</journal>
    <volume>22:145-153,</volume>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>6.</citation-number>
    <author>Koenig, J. Q., W. E. Pierson, M. Horike, and R. Frank.</author>
    <title>Effects of S07 plus NaCl aerosol combined with moderate exercise on pulmonary function in asthmatic adolescents.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Res.</journal>
    <volume>25:340-348,</volume>
    <date>1981.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>7.</citation-number>
    <author>Koenig, J. Q., W. E. Pierson, M. Horike, and R. Frank.</author>
    <title>Bronchoconstrictor responses to sulfur dioxide or sulfur dioxide plus sodium chloride droplets in allergic, nonasthmatic adolescents.</title>
    <journal>J. Allergy Clin. Immunol.</journal>
    <volume>69:339,</volume>
    <date>1982(a).</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>8.</citation-number>
    <author>Koenig, J. Q., W. E. Pierson, M. Horike, and R. Frank.</author>
    <title>Effects of inhaled SO alone and SO + NaCl droplet aerosol on pulmonary function i~ hea~thy adol~scents exposed during r~st and exercise.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health</journal>
    <volume>37:</volume>
    <pages>5-9,</pages>
    <date>1982(b).</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>9.</citation-number>
    <author>Linn, W. S., R. M. Bailey, D. A. Medway,T. G. Venet, L. E. Wigttman and J. D. Hackney.</author>
    <title>Respiratory Responses of YoungAdult Asthmatics to Sulfur Dioxide Exposure under Simulated Ambient Conditions.</title>
    <journal>Environ. Res.</journal>
    <note>(In press, 1982a)</note>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>10.</citation-number>
    <author>Linn, W. S., D. A. Shamoo, C. E. Spier, L. M. Valencia, U. T. Anzar, T. G. Venet and J. D. Hackney.</author>
    <title>Respiratory Effects of 0.75 ppm Sulfur Dioxide in Exercising Asthmatics: Influence of Upper-Respiratory Defenses. Environ. Res.</title>
    <note>(In press, 1982b) ·,, 11.</note>
    <editor>Nadel, J., H. Salem, B. Tamplin, and Y. Tokiwa.</editor>
    <title>Mechanismof bronchoconstriction during inhalation of sulfur dioxide.</title>
    <journal>J. Appl. Physiol.</journal>
    <volume>20:164-167,</volume>
    <date>1965.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>12.</citation-number>
    <author>NIAIDAsthma and other allergic diseases. U.S. Department of Health,</author>
    <title>Education, and Welfare.</title>
    <genre>NIH Publication 79-387,</genre>
    <location>Washington, D.C.,</location>
    <date>1979.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>13.</citation-number>
    <author>Niinimaa, V., P. Cole, S. Mintz and R. J. Shephard.</author>
    <title>Oronasal distribution of respiratory flow.</title>
    <journal>Resp. Physiol</journal>
    <volume>43:</volume>
    <pages>69-75,</pages>
    <date>1981.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>14.</citation-number>
    <author>Senior, R.M., and S. S. Lefrak.</author>
    <title>Status Asthmaticus.</title>
    <container-title>In: Pulmonary Diseases and Disorders. A.P.</container-title>
    <editor>Fishman, ed. McGraw-Hill-;-New York.</editor>
    <pages>pp. 593-599,</pages>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>15.</citation-number>
    <author>Sheppard, D., J. A. Nadel, and H. A. Boushey.</author>
    <title>Inhibition of sulfur dioxide-induced bronchoconstriction by disodium cromoglycate in asthmatic subjects.</title>
    <journal>Am. Rev. Respir. Dis.</journal>
    <volume>124:</volume>
    <pages>257-259,</pages>
    <date>1981a.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>16.</citation-number>
    <author>Sheppard, D., A. Saisho, J. A. Nadel, and H. A. Boushey.</author>
    <title>Exercise increases sulfur dioxide-induced bronchoconstriction in asthmatic subjects.</title>
    <journal>Am. Rev. Respir. Dis.</journal>
    <volume>123:486-491,</volume>
    <date>1981b.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>17.</citation-number>
    <author>Sheppard, D., W. S. Wong, C. F. Uehara, J. A. Nadel, and H. A. Boushey.</author>
    <title>Lower threshold and greater bronchomotor responsiveness of asthmatic subjects to sulfur dioxide.</title>
    <journal>AmRev. Respir. Dis.</journal>
    <volume>122:873-878,</volume>
    <date>1980.</date>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>18.</citation-number>
    <author>Stacy, R. W., D. E. House, M. Friedman, M. Hazucha, J. Green, L. Raggio, and L. J. Roger.</author>
    <title>Effects of 0.75 ppm sulfur dioxide on pulmonary function parameters of normal humansubjects.</title>
    <journal>Arch. Environ. Health,</journal>
    <volume>36:172-178,</volume>
    <date>1981.</date>
    <pages>-</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <author>U.S. Environmenta1Protection Agency r--</author>
    <title>Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office 11.</title>
    <container-title>CONTRACT/GRANT NO. MD-52 Research Triangle Park,</container-title>
    <pages>NC 27711</pages>
  </sequence>
  <sequence>
    <citation-number>12.</citation-number>
    <author>SPONSORING AGENCY NAME ANO ADDRESS 13. TYPE OF REPORT ANO PERIOD COVERED U.S.</author>
    <title>Environmental Protection Agency FINAL Office of Research and Development 14. SPONSORING AGENCY CODE Office of Hea1th and Environmental Assessment EPA/600/00 401 MStreet,</title>
    <journal>SW Washington,</journal>
    <volume>DC 20460</volume>
    <container-title>115,SUPPLEMENTARY NOTES ! 10. ABSTRACT The documentevaluates and assesses scientific information on the health and welfare effects associated with exposure to various concentrations of sulfur oxides and particulate matter in ambient air.</container-title>
    <note>The literature through 1980-81 has been reviewed</note>
  </sequence>
</dataset>
